Samir Lilienfeld, Full-Stack Web Developer

samirlilienfeld@hotmail.com

PROFILE

A Full-Stack Web Developer with experience in crafting responsive UI, building single page applications, developing Web APIs and managing teams in a professional environment using Agile methodology. Skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Java, the Spring Framework and PostgreSQL.

EDUCATION

Lambda School, Full-Stack Web Development

Jul 2019 - May 2020

University of Texas at Austin, Bachelor of Science, Petroleum Engineering

Aug 2011 - May 2015, Austin, TX Business Foundations Certificate, Aug 2015

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Team Lead, Lambda School

Aug 2019 - present, Remote

- Leads a team of seven students that emulates a real work environment using Agile methodology.
- Provides daily feedback and issue resolution through Slack help channel and/or code review.
- Facilitates bi-weekly standup meetings to build camaraderie, facilitate sharing of ideas and provide guidance for that week's study material.

Operations Supervisor, CyraCom International

Sep 2017 - Jun 2019, Houston, TX

- Managed duties, payroll, and performance for 20+ direct reports.
- Developed direct reports' interpretation skills through careful monitoring, timely feedback and constant coaching.
- Responsible for maintaining and debugging Excel spreadsheets that track the attendance of 500+ employees.
- Performed quarterly quality reviews.

Spanish Interpreter, CyraCom International

Feb 2016 - Sep 2017, Houston, TX

 Facilitated access to medical, government and emergency services for individuals with limited English proficiency.

DETAILS

(713) 775-4442

LINKS

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/samir-hub

GitHub

www.github.com/samir-hub

SKILLS

Java

Spring Framework

PostgreSQL

HTML

CSS/LESS/Sass

JavaScript

Excel

Leadership

LANGUAGES

English

Spanish

- Developed vocabulary and pertinent knowledge to assure quality of service.
- Trained and coached new hires to ensure accurate and complete interpretation.

Junior Engineer, Blakely Engineering & Associates, LLC

Apr 2016 - Aug 2016, Houston, TX

- Interpreted daily work over reports to create cohesive and accurate timelines for each well. The timelines
 chronicled changes in tubing and screen configuration, packer and cast iron bridge plug depths, and other
 wellbore variables after each work over operation.
- Designed wellbore schematics using MS Excel and Well Shadow for each well and each work over report. Assured accuracy by matching each well to its corresponding timeline.

Pipeline Engineering Technical Aide, Technip

May 2013 - Aug 2013, Houston, TX

- Participated in the FEED project (installation oriented) for the Anadarko subsea development located in Mozambique. Tasks performed included:
- Collaborated with engineers to gather, finalize and submit engineering reports, including pipe wall thickness calculations, pipeline on-bottom stability analyses and project specifications
- Generated a flowchart to formulate an installation methodology for the project. The project included the
 installation of dual 45-kilometer-long pipelines from the shore to the associated subsea structures,
 manifolds and flow lines. The flowchart included the use of a trenching spread for the shore approach, Slay vessels for shallow water and J-lay vessels for deep water.
- Studied SAGE Profile 3D, a finite element engine used for pipeline analysis. Analyzed and modeled a 10-inch pipeline using SAGE Profile 3D in order to evaluate bottom roughness and areas that required potential span remediation. Prepared a presentation on SAGE Profile 3D using MS Office and then presented it to the Subsea Engineering Manager and Pipeline Department Manager with great success.